A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Special Events and Activities, Beckman Symposium FA888
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Special Events and Activities, Beckman Symposium
1984-1987
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University
FA888
0.88 Cubic Feet 2 document boxes
2 boxes.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 600-18
Biographical/Historical note
The Beckman Symposium on Biomedical Instrumentation was held on April 12, 1985 at The Rockefeller University in New York City. It was held in celebration of the fiftieth anniversary of the founding of Beckman Instruments, Inc.; the eighty-fifth birthday of Arnold O. Beckman; and in conjunction with the seventy-fifth anniversary of the founding of The Rockefeller University Hospital. Participants in the symposium include: Joshua Lederberg, Arnold Thackray & Jeffrey L. Sturchio, Paul F. Cranefield, Vincent P. Dole, Manuel Gordon, Howard K. Schachman, Koji Nakanishi, C.H.W. Hirs, Bruce Merrifield, and Charles Coulter. A book was published in 1986, which included the proceedings of the symposium. It was edited by Carol L. Moberg, who also gave the papers to the archives.
Scope and Contents
Contains biographical materials, symposium materials, correspondence, memoranda, audio.
Medical research; Medicine, Preventive; Biology -- Research; Vivisection; Medical sciences; Medical care; Cell and biomolecular sciences; Genetics; DNA; China
- Audio tapes, 1985 April 12 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Access copy currently unavailable. Please see a RAC archivist for further instruction.
- Biographical Material on Participants, including A. Beckman (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Computer Disks of Symposium Proceedings (Box 1, Folder 3)
  RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
- Copyright Registration and Author Agreements, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence (also includes drafts of speeches)
  - Coulter, Charles L., 1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Cranefield, Paul F., 1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Dole, Vincent P., 1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Gordon, Manuel J., 1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Hirs, Christopher, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Lederberg, Joshua, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Merrifield, Bruce, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Nakanishi, Koji, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Schachman, Howard K., 1985 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Thackray, Arnold, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Illustrations for Papers (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Page Proofs
  - Final (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - First Set (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Second Set (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Transcripts of Tapes (Original) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - (The Beckman Symposium on Biomedical Instrumentation, edited by Carol L. Moberg, Fullerton, CA: The Rockefeller University in association with Beckman Instruments, Inc., 1986), 2 copies
- Plenary Session - Monday morning (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Press - Directory (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Press - Invitations, Logo, Tags (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Press - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Publicity and Press (Box 4, Folder 1)
- RUnion Committee (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Samples of RU Printed Material and Letters (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Son's & Daughter's Program (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Tent, Caps, and Gowns (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Working Group (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Talks given by: David Rockefeller, Joshua Lederberg, Gerald Edelman, and David Baltimore, 4 cassettes (Box 4)
- 25th Anniversary Reunion and Convocation 10-12 June 1984 Edited Master (in film vault), 1984 June 10-12; video (Box 4)